[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 11]
What are you doing?
Master.
I now know I was wrong.
Everything that has happened
is all my fault.
I shouldn't have disobeyed
my parents' orders
and insisted on marrying you
as a concubine.
I shouldn't have counted on you
to shield the three of us
from life's harships.
It's all my fault.
What do you mean?
Are you saying you were
blind to marry me?
How dare you!
Master.
No matter what,
Zhengjun is your own flesh and blood.
Even if he’s made a thousand mistakes,
you can't just stand by
and watch him fend for himself
in prison, can you?
Concubine Mei.
Mei Yinghua.
Everyone in the residence knows
that I dote on you the most.
Otherwise, how would I put up with you
causing trouble all the time?
If I didn't care for
that little brat,
why would I personally go to the prison
and give him 70 lashes?
70 lashes?
You might as well take his life!
Such a narrow-minded view.
If I didn't give him 70 lashes,
would that guy surnamed Yan
actually believe he was framed?
I saved his life!
70 lashes is already
letting him off easy.
I don't care.
Either way, you must get him out of prison.
If you don't save Zhengjun,
I'll die right in front of you.
Then die.
Master!
The Eldest Young Master is back!
Mother!
[Xie's Eldest Young Master, Xie Zhenglun]
Get up.
My son has grown taller.
This is Zhenglun, the Eldest Brother
everyone talks about.
I have been thinking about you every day.
Zhengjun, he...
Mother.
I'm here.
It seems
he is Concubine Mei's weakness.
Xie Shu
wants me to take the fall for this
corruption charge all by myself.
Yan Rui
wants to use my life
in exchange for merits.
Fine.
Then we shall
gamble our lives with them once more.
Second Young Master,
your time has come.
Lord Yan!
Save me!
I have accepted Lord Wei's gift
on his behalf.
As for Second Young Master Xie,
you must not touch him.
What else do you have up your sleeves?
Don't kill him!
[Shen Che]
Here are the noodles you wanted.
I made this for you myself.
Eat up.
Your skills have regressed.
That's for sure.
As a corrupt official
living a life of pleasure and
leisure every day,
my skills naturally can't compare to yours.
You are all alone in the capital.
It must have been hard on you.
Eat slowly.
Since you are back,
why don't you stay for a few more days?
I've prepared a room for you.
I still have some things to do.
After you finish eating,
rest early.
I recall ordering that
during the lockdown of the Xie Residence,
no one is allowed to enter or leave.
Yes.
Then thank you for doing me a favor,
Lord Yan.
So you're relying on my authority
to throw your weight around now.
Tell me.
What brings you here so late at night?
If you can't give me a convincing reason,
I'll escort you back
to the residence myself.
Since I left Chen's Tea House,
it's been a long time since
I had osmanthus candy with
such a strong flavor.
Miss, don't tell me you
went through all the trouble of
escaping from the residence
just to trick me out of candy.
What's up?
You wanted to see me?
Yes.
I missed you.
At the same time,
I also want to tell you something.
Lord Yan,
can you withdraw your troops?
What a letdown.
I put on such a big show
just to be able to see you every day.
If I withdraw my troops,
wouldn't that put me far away from you?
♪ The immortal with green hair ♪
♪ Lazy and flirtatious ♪
What's wrong?
♪ Drinking toasts ♪
Xie Shu said
that the first time he met my mother,
she was singing Tale of the Pipa.
The way her water sleeves danced
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into
the depths of the night ♪
looked exactly like a butterfly.
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away
the heat burning in my eyes ♪
Unfortunately,
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom,
then quietly fall ♪
I've never heard my mother sing opera.
♪ Only then do I understand right
from what's wrong and bitter ♪
I wonder if it's really
as beautiful as he described.
♪ Pear blossoms drift through the courtyard,
fluttering like snowflakes in a song ♪
My mother once said
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
she also yearned for an unwavering love.
♪  Which moment is hypothetical,
and which is a real choice? ♪
But ever since I can remember,
she had became a different person.
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
She stopped singing opera
and no longer had any desires.
♪ I wonder why joy is always
so scarce in this world ♪
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
In this inner court,
there lived so many women.
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks
oflife and death ♪
My mother was just one of them.
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
Her smiles,
her tears,
her dreams,
has been buried in
this inner courtyard.
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into
the depths of the night ♪
Xie Qingyuan.
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away
the heat burning in my eyes ♪
Have you ever loved a woman?
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom,
then quietly fall ♪
♪ Only then do I understand right
from what's wrong and bitter ♪
What kind of question is that?
♪ Pear blossoms drift through the courtyard,
fluttering like snowflakes in a song ♪
I just want to know
under what circumstances
a man would give up
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
the woman he loves.
♪  Which moment is hypothetical,
and which is a real choice? ♪
In order to protect her.
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
♪ I wonder why joy is always
so scarce in this world ♪
Let my Second Brother go.
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
Yan Rui.
You clearly know
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks
oflife and death ♪
that my Second Brother is simply
the most insignificant little shrimp
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
in this murky waters of Hengtang.
What you want to catch
♪ The wind blows away old memories,
piling them in heaps before the door ♪
is the big fish behind him, right?
Am I right?
♪ No one speaks for anyone else ♪
♪ Which page is a missed opportunity,
and which holds my hopes? ♪
[Xie Residence of Hengtang]
His Lordship has ordered
to withdraw the guards
and return.
[Xie Residence of Hengtang]
Yes, Sir!
Thank you, Lord Yan.
Zhenglun.
Yes.
Take your brother to rest and recover.
Yes, Father.
A trip to the Criminal Justice Office
has taken a heavy toll on him.
Second Brother cares most about
preserving his reputation.
When has he ever been subject to
such injustice?
Second Young Master Xie was the victim of
an assassination attempt yesterday.
It looks like he is still a little shaken.
Lord Xie,
please prepare some
calming herbal soups for him.
Did you say... assassination?
What do you mean?
I suppose since the case is
about to be solved,
someone wanted to make a
last-ditch attempt.
But rest assured, Lord Xie.
Your son is fine.
He only suffered some minor injuries
and a little hardship.
The hardship...
is also his own fault.
Indeed.
Second Young Master is young and ignorant.
He fell for Guo Baofeng's tricks
and resold the disaster relief grain.
Although he is guilty,
fortunately he is not the mastermind.
Besides, the money has been compensated.
So for this case...
Lord Yan.
The tea beside you
is lotus seed tea prepared by
my daughter Qingyuan herself.
It clears inner heat
and relieves worries.
Please have a taste.
The tea brewed by Fourth Lady
is indeed delicious.
Since that's the case,
how about closing the case after autumn?
That way, everyone will be happy.
Sounds great.
Thank you.
No need to thank me.
You should thank Fourth Lady.
If she hadn't persuaded me
with her eloquence,
I don't think this matter
would have been settled so quickly.
In that case,
I owe the greatest thanks to myself
for having such a wonderful daughter.
Qingyuan.
Lord Yan
is generous and righteous.
You should pick a day
to visit the Yan residence
and formally thank him in person.
Yes.
Indeed.
The Eighteen Scholars Camellias
at my residence
are blooming beautifully.
Please stop by whenever
you have some free time.
Yes.
I, Xie Shu, stand ready to
receive the decree.
It seems Lord Xie
knew the Emperor would do this.
Commissioner Hu's influence
in the court
is truly not to be underestimated.
The Emperor's grace is vast.
I am deeply grateful.
Since the Emperor trusts Lord Xie so much,
I'm sure you will not disappoint him
and resolve the disaster relief efforts.
The corruption and famine in Hengtang
are about to be resolved.
I hope Lord Xie can lend a hand
and help me out.
Of course.
No problem at all.
[Moonlight Casts Its Radiance]
Father.
What are you doing?
[Moonlight Casts Its Radiance]
Second Brother has already been punished
for his mistakes.
My mother simply loves her son dearly
and didn't mean to be disrespectful to you.
Please lift the detention order.
Zhengjun...
still needs his mother's care.
Are there not enough maids and nannies
in the residence?
Do you really need that
good-for-nothing mother of yours
to take care of the injured?
My mother has been prideful her whole life.
It's really pitiful to
treat her this way.
Pitiful?
She brought it upon herself.
Only a fool like you
would be fooled by her tears.
When I was in the Northern Frontier,
how many times did I tell you?
A man
must not be soft-hearted.
We have guests in the residence.
Lord Yan will head out soon.
How would it look if he saw you
kneeling here?
Are you trying to embarrass me?
I wouldn't dare.
Get up.
The Fourth Lady has always
been bold and reckless.
Just now,
you even dared to eavesdrop on
the Emperor's secrets.
You knew I was here
but you didn't say anything.
That means you tacitly
allowed me to listen in,
so it's not eavesdropping.
You are just twisting the truth.
I really didn't mean to eavesdrop.
I came to inform Your Lordship
that your personal belongings
have been loaded onto the carriage.
You can leave at any time.
What?
Burning bridges?
So eager to kick me out?
Who was the one who cited laws one by one
just to make me stay?
Your Lordship,
shouldn't you be magnanimous?
Why bicker with a weak woman like me?
I am not magnanimous.
I'm the kind of person who
nitpicks everything.
Then what do you want, Your Lordship?
Wait for my word.
There will be times when I will need you.
The notoginseng powder for
Yuanwai's Residence on the East Street?
How dare you little brat even try to
get involved in a deal worth
a hundred taels of silver?
Can you tell the difference
between a 20-head
and a 40-head?
Wenshan panax notoginseng.
The main root looks like a lion's head,
and the cross-section
looks like a chrysanthemum.
It's a shame they overdid it
with the sulfur.
Even the copper scale pan has turned green.
Fine.
Since Fourth Lady knows these herbs,
then do you know
the difference between Qingbei and Songbei?
You should know that
one must not be careless with medicine.
One wrong herb and it could mean...
The ones with a crescent shape
in the middle are the highest grade,
while those that vary greatly in size
are of the next grade.
What's so hard about that?
Just like how you
delivered 5 taels of bird's nest
to the Xie Residence,
but recorded it as 8 taels.
Did you really think the fake bird's nests
made of rice paste
would go unnoticed?
The person recommended by
Second Madam Mei is indeed capable.
Look at your fat face.
You must have been
feeding yourself with
all that extra profit, right?
You are making baseless accusations!
You all are making baseless accusations!
Don't think just because you took over
this pharmacy from Second Madam,
you can do whatever you want.
Who doesn't know that you,
Fourth Lady Xie,
have always been at odds with Second Madam?
Baseless accusations?
Do you really think
I'm a cold-hearted master?
Come,
listen up.
Besides these substandard herbs,
there's a drawer full of
fake donkey-hide gelatin.
And on the third shelf of cabinet C
in the warehouse,
12 bags of Sichuan pepper
are waiting to be mixed with sawdust.
Am I right?
And your little grandson's
tuition at the private academy
in the south of the city
is paid from the Xie Residence's
public account, right?
Who approved this?
How dare you!
So you're just here to cause trouble, huh?
-I’ll…
-Guards!
Hurry up, grab your employment contract,
and get out of here!
Bullying the outnumbered?
Just you wait!
My son.
Your father has agreed to let you out.
The Xie family is safe.
As for this Fourth Lady,
if you truly love her
and refuse to marry anyone else,
I won't stop you anymore.
I just beg you not to
torture yourself like this anymore.
Okay.
Go wash up and change your clothes.
How can you go to see your loved one
without looking your best?
Thank you, Mother.
Young Master Li.
A few pearls have accidentally fallen off
the jade and pearl hairpin
you left at the Xie Residence last time
I have sent someone to repair it.
When it is fixed,
♪ If the wind softly whispers your name ♪
I will send someone to
deliver it back to your residence.
Why?
Don't you like it, Qingyuan?
Yes.
I don't like it.
♪ If my heart softly hears your voice ♪
♪ I'm still here,
holding on to our memories ♪
By not liking it,
I don't mean the hairpin is not good.
It deserves a better owner
♪ Quietly waiting in the passage of time
for a reply ♪
who will cherish it.
Just like you, Young Master Li.
♪ Listening to every word, every line,
everything about you ♪
All the ladies in Hengtang
say you are the best candidate
for a husband,
because you are outstanding.
♪ Your gentle breath,
the traces left by longing ♪
But to like someone,
you don't need them to be outstanding.
Just liking them is enough.
♪ No sight could ever compare to you,
forever in my heart ♪
But I like you.
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become
part of your journey ♪
Since the Shangsi Festival,
I have decided I will marry no one but you.
Can you tell me why
you are always trying to push me away?
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
Am I inadequate in any way
that made you hate me?
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
I don't hate you.
But it doesn't mean
that I will definitely like you.
When it comes to interacting with others,
isn’t being at ease
the most important thing?
It's true.
I am a concubine-born daughter
of the Xie family.
After wandering in exile for many years,
♪ If the wind softly whispers your name ♪
I need to tread lightly
just to survive in this house.
♪ If my heart softly hears your voice ♪
But Young Master Li,
although I live in such an environment,
it doesn't mean I need a man
♪ I'm still here,
holding on to our memories ♪
or a marriage to save me.
Do you understand what I mean?
♪ Quietly waiting in the passage of time
for a reply ♪
♪ Listening to every word, every line,
everything about you ♪
♪ Your gentle breath,
the traces left by longing ♪
Just like this beam of light,
to me,
♪ No sight could ever compare to you,
forever in my heart ♪
it means nothing.
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become
part of your journey ♪
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
It's okay.
I will always be by your side.
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
Trust me,
one day I'll let you see my true feelings.
♪ No sight could ever compare to you,
forever in my heart ♪
[Frugality Cultivates Virtue]
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become
part of your journey ♪
Where were we?
We were talking about the ledger.
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
Who is that?
Who?
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
The two of them on the bridge.
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
The Fourth Lady of the Xie family.
She's a knife in my hand.
Fine.
Just don't let the knife
cut your own hand instead.
I know what I'm doing.
It's no big deal.
I won't let her
get in the way of our plan.
Don't you dare touch her.
Yan.
Dear.
I prepared some candies for you.
Take them home.
This is sugar pastry.
When there's sugar, there's joy
This is lotus seed candy.
More sons, more blessings.
You two continue to chat.
I'm going to make some sugar syrup.
Thank you, Granny.
What does "more sons, more blessings"
even mean?
You are not allowed to have it.
Why?
Could Granny have poisoned it?
Shouldn't you give me some reward for
meeting you in the middle of the night?
What is it, Lord Yan?
There is indeed something
I need you to do for me.
It might require someone.
Who?
Li Congxin.
Please trouble me with something else.
I don't stand a chance with
the Marquis of Danyang household.
Others might not be able to do it.
But with your intelligence
and your relationship with Young Master Li,
isn't this a piece of cake?
I am not close to Young Master Li.
I'm afraid
he wouldn't be up to the task.
Is that so?
When the Xie family was in danger,
your so-called "not close" Young Master Li
came to propose without hesitation.
Forgot?
Even I was moved.
Looking at it this way,
Young Master Li is simple
and straightforward.
He never hides anything.
He is indeed a good match.
At least he is better than
some old foxes who have
a dozen tricks up their sleeves.
Even when we sit down for a cup of tea,
we’re still suspicious of each other
and testing the waters.
Shopkeeper!
What kind of snacks
do you have in the shop today?
Let me have a look.
We have a great variety here.
Sir,
from the sound of it,
you've never been to our shop before.
Not bad.
How long has this shop been opened?
I've been here for half of my life.
Foxes are skilled at
winning people's hearts.
You said I'm a fox.
Have you perhaps
lost something to me?
I've long heard that
your shop has good snacks.
Even the Imperial Advisor, Lord Yan,
comes here often.
Yan Rui, you...
Today, I must see
what's so special about your snacks.
Aren't you afraid your father's colleague
will find out that we met here
in the middle of the night?
We have poria cakes!
Then I'll have some poria cakes.
My Lord!
Poria cakes are in the front hall.
Let's go.
I'll take you to pick more snacks.
You know,
we have many kinds of poria cake,
and even fresh glutinous dumplings.
I'll pick a few nice things for you today.
These are all great picks for
this time of year.
What should I do?
You have a captivating charm.
You give me...
butterflies in my stomach.
You sure talk a lot of nonsense.
They haven't left yet.
You can't wait to leave, huh?
What?
Are you afraid I'll eat you?
♪ You, tender yet sharp,
with thorns by your side ♪
I'm just your weapon.
Yet, you seem to care so much about
how a weapon feels.
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
Could it be...
that you have other feelings for me?
♪ The wind and rain sigh,
the road stretches far ♪
I do have special feelings for you.
♪ Blossoms drift with streams,
affections softly stir ♪
♪ Half real, half illusion;
one cup of spring awakes me ♪
♪ Burned and released,
held by fate's hand ♪
If that's your plan,
♪ Greet the soft, mild evening breeze
and homebound sail to land ♪
why are you still afraid of Wei Changyan?
♪ Slim moonbeams
weave tangled dreams all night ♪
When have I been afraid of him?
♪ Lonely home boat glides slow
through dark twilight ♪
Since you call me a fox,
♪ I walk and gaze; one cup of spring
fades to lingering cheer ♪
I must not disappoint you.
What you just said
♪ I chant and sigh; one cup of spring,
drunk through turns of year ♪
concerns the safety of
the people of Hengtang.
So of course I'll do my best.
But there's one more thing
I would like to ask for your help.
Go ahead.
I'll do my best to help you too.
Help me find Cui'er,
the drug-testing slave,
who was sold to the Xie family
28 years ago.
You still want to
overturn your mother's case?
I live...
just to clear my mother's name.
I don't mean anything else.
Qingyuan!
Speak of the devil.
Your perfect match is here,
Qingyuan.
Young Master Li.
Zhenglun received premium-grade Yuanhong
and invited me over for a drink.
Would you like to join us?
Is someone else here?
Why are you here?
I came to buy snacks
and ran into her.
She told me
a lot of nice things about you.
Really?
Yes.
So many nice things.
Fourth Lady,
why don't you tell him yourself?
What did you say?
If there is nothing else,
I'll go back with him.
You are in?
Lord Yan,
see you.
Take care.
I'll take it.
No need.
It's okay.
Let me.
Thank you, Young Master Li.
What is that?
It's here!
When did you pick it?
It doesn't matter.
What matters is...
No matter how sweet the candy,
as long as there's someone
you want but can't get,
you taste nothing but bitterness.
You think too much.
I have no feelings for her.
I just want her to do a few things for me.
As for you,
you've been following me all day.
Aren't you tired?
It better be.
If you let your romantic interests
get in the way of our grand plan,
I will definitely kill her first
to prevent future troubles.
You have evidence of Wei Changyan's crimes.
He won't just sit and wait for death.
You don't have any bargaining chips.
Be careful not to fumble over
something unexpected.
Enough.
Tell me.
How are the grain prices now?
I've been at the border for years.
It's rare for me to return to Hengtang.
I never expected to cross paths
with the two of you
and help bring about something good.
Chen's Tea House?
I think the lotus candies given to Qingyuan
may be good as wedding candies.
Actually, that day,
I saw that the Xie family
was in a dire situation.
My rash proposal
was only to force Yan Rui to retreat.
Besides,
I didn't get Qingyuan's agreement.
Let's just treat this matter as a joke.
Since you are so affectionate,
maybe one day,
Qingyuan will be moved.
The two of you,
please don't make fun of me.
I have a lowly status
and wouldn't dare to associate myself
with the Marquis' household.
But you did save me from danger that day.
I will never forget this kindness.
I offer my pure heart with this jade flask.
A toast you, Young Master Li.
Alright.
But please, Qingyuan,
forget my identity from now on,
and forget my name.
Just remember that for you,
my heart is brighter than the moon,
and I'd die for you.
Chunzhi!
Don't drink it.
Second Sister,
What are you doing?
If Baoxian hadn't slipped up
and let me know you were drinking here,
she would have had her way.
Brother Chunzhi,
don't let this bad person fool you.
Second Sister,
why are you attacking
your own family like this?
Second Sister.
I have never lied to you,
nor have I lied to Young Master Li.
Is there some misunderstanding
between you and me?
Misunderstanding?
I really don't want to talk about
the ugly things you did.
Since childhood, everyone knew
that Brother Chunzhi and I
were the closest.
But after you showed up?
He's always on your side
and even wanted to marry you.
Second Sister,
where is this coming from?
I...
My kindness to you
has always been because
I see you as a sibling,
as my own younger sister.
-I truly have feelings for Qingyuan.
-Young Master Li.
I have no intention of interfering
with the relationship between
Second Sister and yourself.
I have overstepped and offended you today.
I apologize to everyone,
and will not disturb you any longer.
Qingyuan!